<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>NSWindow on Flying blind - coding nonsense</title><link>https://kicsipixel.github.io/tags/NSWindow/</link><description>Recent content in NSWindow on Flying blind - coding nonsense</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kicsipixel.github.io/tags/NSWindow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>NSWindow without Storyboard but...</title><link>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2020/2020-10-28-semistoryboard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2020/2020-10-28-semistoryboard/</guid><description>Earlier this year I wrote a short blog post about creating NSWindow without Storyboard with code only. While collecting information, I read several opinions why it was a tedious job, and it could be done better&amp;hellip;
Maybe the easiest way to mix Storyboard and coding approach. As I pointed out, recreation of NSMenu is a real pain/mess. So, what about keeping Main.storyboard for NSMenu only and code the rest of the components?</description></item><item><title>NSWindow without Storyboard</title><link>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2020/2020-01-11-nostoryboard/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2020/2020-01-11-nostoryboard/</guid><description>Time to time the debate restarts whether using Storyboard is the proper way of interface desing. On iPhone it is quite simple and you can find several articles or tutorials. I wanted to try it on macOS and hardly found anything up-to-date information. Hereby I share what I found, maybe it can help others.
At the end of the article I indicated all the sources I used.
Step 1. Create a new Swift project with Storyboard.</description></item><item><title>Custom NSWindow</title><link>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2020/2020-01-10-customnswindow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2020/2020-01-10-customnswindow/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re completely bored by gray-backgrounded NSWindow and wondering how to improve the UI with some colors, here we go with some helps. I highly recommend Luka Kerr&amp;rsquo;s post on Github. We will build this: Step 1. Create a project in XCode with Swift and Storyboard. Step 2. Add a new NSWindowController.swift file to the project Step 3. Connect the new custom controller with Storyboard element Step 4. Add some code to our CustomWindowController.</description></item></channel></rss>