<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>NSTableView on Flying blind - coding nonsense</title><link>https://kicsipixel.github.io/tags/NSTableView/</link><description>Recent content in NSTableView on Flying blind - coding nonsense</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kicsipixel.github.io/tags/NSTableView/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>NSTableView with Cocoa Bindings</title><link>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2020/2020-04-30-bindings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2020/2020-04-30-bindings/</guid><description>I think Cocoa Bindings is a little bit controversial technology. Some people believe less code means less error, easier to debug, according to the others it is hard to read and understand, it&amp;rsquo;s black magic. During the years I tried to understand several times with very little luck. Last night I read a brilliant book by Stuart Grimshaw. I highly recommend his book, he wrote a lot of very useful concept about general programming and Swift coding as well.</description></item><item><title>Very simple view-based NSTableView in Swift 4.2 using Model</title><link>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2018/2018-11-17-nstableview_2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2018/2018-11-17-nstableview_2/</guid><description>This tutorial is very similar to the previous one, the only difference that now, we will use a Person model, that will make you life easier.
So, the final will be the same: Step 1. Create a Cocoa Application project. Step 2. Add NSTableView to the Main Storyboard and customize a little bit Increase the number of columns from 2 to 3. Click on the header and name the columns We need to add identifier to the columns and cells.</description></item><item><title>Very simple view-based NSTableView in Swift 4.2</title><link>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2018/2018-11-16-nstableview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2018/2018-11-16-nstableview/</guid><description>It is widely known that while the internet is full with iOS tutorials you hardly find any Cocoa ones. Many things on iOS with CocoaTouch is simpler than on OS X, so it is not obvious that after reading some tutorials, you will be able code on both platform.
I’d like to share what I learn helping others and receiving advises from experienced fellows. My first application is a simple phonebook using view-based NSTableView.</description></item></channel></rss>