<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Storyboard on Flying blind - coding nonsense</title><link>https://kicsipixel.github.io/tags/Storyboard/</link><description>Recent content in Storyboard on Flying blind - coding nonsense</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kicsipixel.github.io/tags/Storyboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>NSWindow without Storyboard but...</title><link>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2020/2020-10-28-semistoryboard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2020/2020-10-28-semistoryboard/</guid><description>Earlier this year I wrote a short blog post about creating NSWindow without Storyboard with code only. While collecting information, I read several opinions why it was a tedious job, and it could be done better&amp;hellip;
Maybe the easiest way to mix Storyboard and coding approach. As I pointed out, recreation of NSMenu is a real pain/mess. So, what about keeping Main.storyboard for NSMenu only and code the rest of the components?</description></item><item><title>KVO, KVC and Bindings</title><link>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2020/2020-06-02-kvc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2020/2020-06-02-kvc/</guid><description>The original tutorial was published in Cocoa Programming for OS X: The Big Nerd Ranch Guide in April, 2015. As far as I know this was last macOS/AppKit/Cocoa book by Aaron Hillegass, later he published only about iOS/UIKit. Although the book was written for Xcode 6.3 and Swift 1.2 it is a very interesting and useful reading in case you are interested in macOS programming.
We will create a simple Thermostat app with minimal code using KVC.</description></item><item><title>NSTableView with Cocoa Bindings</title><link>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2020/2020-04-30-bindings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2020/2020-04-30-bindings/</guid><description>I think Cocoa Bindings is a little bit controversial technology. Some people believe less code means less error, easier to debug, according to the others it is hard to read and understand, it&amp;rsquo;s black magic. During the years I tried to understand several times with very little luck. Last night I read a brilliant book by Stuart Grimshaw. I highly recommend his book, he wrote a lot of very useful concept about general programming and Swift coding as well.</description></item><item><title>NSWindow without Storyboard</title><link>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2020/2020-01-11-nostoryboard/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kicsipixel.github.io/posts/2020/2020-01-11-nostoryboard/</guid><description>Time to time the debate restarts whether using Storyboard is the proper way of interface desing. On iPhone it is quite simple and you can find several articles or tutorials. I wanted to try it on macOS and hardly found anything up-to-date information. Hereby I share what I found, maybe it can help others.
At the end of the article I indicated all the sources I used.
Step 1. Create a new Swift project with Storyboard.</description></item></channel></rss>